Do you enjoy playing computer games?
你喜欢玩电脑游戏吗？
They can be thrilling, especially when you’re competing against others.
它们往往令人兴奋不已，尤其是在与他人竞技的时候。
They involve lots of skill, and offer a chance to switch off from the pressures of real life.
游戏需要高超的技巧，还能让人暂时摆脱现实生活的压力。
But imagine if your gaming talents could actually be put to use in the real world?
但试想一下，如果你的游戏天赋真的能在现实世界中派上用场呢？
Well, now businesses are waking up to the skills gamers can bring to the workplace.
如今，企业正逐渐意识到游戏玩家能为职场带来的特殊技能。
As an example, the BBC spoke to trainee surgeon Saied Froghi.
比如，英国广播公司采访了实习外科医生赛义德·弗罗吉。
He played video games like Age of Empires and Halo in his spare time when he was at medical school.
他在医学院读书时，闲暇时间会玩《帝国时代》《光晕》等电子游戏。
But this relaxing pastime wasn’t distracting him from his studies - he thinks his time in front of a screen actually helped his surgery skills.
但这种放松方式并没有影响他的学业——他认为，长时间面对屏幕实际上提升了他的手术技能。
He claims it helped him with his concentration, and he compares some of the skills used in keyhole surgery with using a games console. He says “Your hands know where the buttons are and how to rotate the instrument.”
他表示，游戏帮助他提高了专注力，还将微创手术中用到的一些技能与操作游戏手柄进行类比：“你的手会本能地知道按钮的位置，以及如何转动器械。”
Certainly, operating gaming controls help to develop good hand-eye coordination, but there are other abilities you can learn which can be applied to real-life work situations.
当然，操作游戏控制器有助于培养良好的手眼协调能力，但游戏还能让人学到其他可应用于现实工作场景的能力。
Start-up company Game Academy told the BBC’s David Molloy that some games involve strategy and resource management, which are good skills for management.
初创公司“游戏学院”（Game Academy）告诉英国广播公司的大卫·莫洛伊，一些游戏涉及战略规划和资源管理，这些都是宝贵的管理技能。
It analyses gamers' habits from their online gaming profile and offers courses in valuable skills that reflect their aptitudes.
该公司通过玩家的在线游戏档案分析他们的行为习惯，并提供与其天赋相匹配的实用技能课程。
These are skills that can be developed, and if carefully reworded, can be added to CVs.
这些技能不仅可以进一步培养，经过恰当的措辞包装后，还能被写进个人简历。
Employers might still need convincing that gamers are not just teenagers wasting their time in their bedrooms without thinking about their career prospects.
雇主们可能仍需要一些时间来相信，游戏玩家并非只是在卧室里浪费时间、不考虑职业前景的青少年。
But business consultant Mia Bennett told the BBC that gaming can help skills like "decision-making, the ability to anticipate and scenario planning…
但商业顾问米娅·贝内特向英国广播公司表示，游戏能培养“决策能力、预判能力和场景规划能力……
It also helps with meta-skills - learning how to learn, experimentation, and creative thinking."
还能提升元技能——即学习如何学习、尝试探索和创造性思维的能力。”
You might think that the idea of gaming developing transferable skills is like the games themselves – pure fantasy – and a gamer doesn’t want to associate the fun and escapism it provides with work.
你可能会觉得，“游戏能培养可迁移技能”的说法就像游戏本身一样——纯属幻想，而且玩家也不想把游戏带来的乐趣和逃避现实的体验与工作联系起来。
It certainly doesn’t guarantee you a good job, and you need to be an accomplished gamer for your skills to shine.
当然，玩游戏并不能保证你找到一份好工作，只有技艺精湛的玩家，其技能才能脱颖而出。
But if so much time is being spent gripped by the challenge of Portal or the strategy of Civilization, why not put those talents to good use?
但如果我们已经花费了大量时间沉浸在《传送门》的挑战或《文明》的战略布局中，为什么不把这些天赋好好利用起来呢？